<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Meetup on dahernan&#39;s blog </title>
    <link>http://dahernan.github.io/tags/meetup/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <author>Enthusiastic Hugo User</author>
    <rights>Copyright (c) 2014, Enthusiastic Hugo User; all rights reserved.</rights>
    <updated>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang Taipei Gathering</title>
      <link>http://dahernan.github.io/2015/10/12/golang-taipei-gathering/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Enthusiastic Hugo User</author>
      <guid>http://dahernan.github.io/2015/10/12/golang-taipei-gathering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A week ago, taking advance of my trip to Taiwan I had the opportunity to assist and speak at the &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.kktix.cc/events/gtg15&#34;&gt;Golang Taipe Gathering #15&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/taipei4.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event was hosted by the company who made &lt;a href=&#34;http://cardinalblue.com/&#34;&gt;PicCollage&lt;/a&gt;.It&amp;rsquo;s a little app to make a collage of photos, is very popular is Asia (over 12 million active users), and that&amp;rsquo;s probably one of the reasons that Go is very popular in Asia, you have lots of users, so you need technology easy to scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed a lot the talk by &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/kerkerj&#34;&gt;Jerry Huang&lt;/a&gt; about Gobot with one of the Sphero balls. The presentation was in Chinese, but the slides were in English so it was not very difficult to follow even I don&amp;rsquo;t understand any Chinese word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/taipei2.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My presentation was about how to implement Microservices in Go, based in the work that I did for my last client. As a take out, is good to have a complete self explained slides when you are presenting for a non English speakers, it makes much easier to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/taipei1.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the talk, &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/hSATAC&#34;&gt;Ash&lt;/a&gt; the organiser of the meetup, and his friend &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/j100002ben&#34;&gt;Benjamin&lt;/a&gt; take us out for dinner in a local place, were the food was awesome! Thank you so much guys, was so much fun!.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/images/taipei3.png&#34; alt=&#34;alt&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>